Guide to the Milton Barnes papers, 1853-1891
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Milton Barnes papers
1853-1891
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Milton Barnes, 1830-1895
C0065
2 linear feet (4 boxes)
This collection contains two hundred items, mostly correspondence between Milton and Rhoda Barnes during the Civil War. The remainder of the collection consists of documents concerning Milton Barnes as Secretary of State, Rhoda Barnes, and photographs of both.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Mrs. Kathryn Barnes, and her sons James A. Barnes and C. Cortlandt Barnes donated the Milton Barnes Papers to George Mason University in 1975. Mrs. Barnes is the widow of a direct descendant of Milton and Rhoda Barnes.
Biographical Information
Milton Barnes was a recently married lawyer in Cambridge, Ohio, when the Civil War began. He served first as a captain, commanding G Company of the 62nd Ohio Volunteer Infantry Regiment. This unit participated in the first Federal invasion of the Shenandoah Valley in the spring of 1862. When the 62nd Ohio was transferred to the Rappahannock in mid-1862, Captain Barnes was discharged on medical grounds and returned briefly to Cambridge, Ohio.
Later in 1862 he obtained an appointment as lieutenant colonel of the 97th Ohio Volunteer Infantry Regiment and served as its deputy commander and often-acting commander until mustered out in June 1865. Lieutenant Colonel Barnes fought with the 97th Ohio in major engagements in Kentucky, Tennessee, and Georgia until wounded at Kennesaw Mountain, Georgia, in June 1864. He returned to the field in time to take part in the defense of Tennessee against the Confederate re-invasion and was again wounded at Nashville, Tennessee in December 1864. The remainder of his and the 97th Ohio's service was on provost duty at Huntsville, Alabama, and in the East Tennessee mountains on guard against a last possible threat from the failing Confederates in Virginia.
His war letters include first-hand accounts of several battles, notably Stones River (Murfreesboro) and Missionary Ridge at Chattanooga, as well as, details of ordinary life on campaign and in camp. The occasional gaps in the correspondence were mostly the result of several campaigning which left no time for writing. His wife's letters include political news and comments as well as family matters.
After the war, Barnes resumed law practice in Cambridge. In 1867 he was brevetted Colonel in the Volunteer Force, AUS, to date from March 13, 1865 for "gallant and meritorious service" in the war. He was elected Secretary of State for Ohio for two terms (1877-1881) and later served for a year (1891-1892) as special Treasury Agent for Alaska. A lengthy account of his arrival and duties at St. George Island in the Bering Sea is included in the collection.
Scope and Content
This collection contains two hundred items, mostly correspondence between Milton and Rhoda Barnes during the Civil War. The remainder of the collection consists of documents concerning Milton Barnes as Secretary of State, Rhoda Barnes, and photographs of both.
Arrangement
Organized by date.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the Alexander Haight Civil War collection.
Index Terms
Persons:
Barnes, Milton, 1830-1895.; Barnes, Rhoda.
Corporate Names:
United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 67th (1861-1865). Company G.
Geographical Names:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives.
Contents List
  - See accession folder, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Rhoda Allison to her "mothers and grandmothers", April 11, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    West Academy - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 14, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Camp Goddard, Ohio - ALS, 1 page
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 14, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Cambridge, Ohio - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, Cambridge, Ohio - November 28, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lieutenant J. Johnson to Captain Milton Barnes, February 5, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Camp Kelley, Ohio - ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 3, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Winchester, Virginia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 6, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Strasburg, Virginia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 10, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Woodstock, Virginia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 19, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    New Market, Virginia - ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 22, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    New Market, Virginia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Robert A. Allison, May 2, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 4, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Harrisonburg, Virginia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 11, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Cambridge, Ohio - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 18, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 8, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Covington, Kentucky - ALS, 1 page
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 10/12, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Covington, Kentucky - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 11, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 14, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Covington, Kentucky - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 15, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Cambridge, Ohio - ALS, 6 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 21/23, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 24, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Louisville, Kentucky - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 28, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 28, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 30, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Louisville, Kentucky - ALS, 3 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, October 2, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, October 5/6, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 13/16, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Danville, Kentucky - ALS, 6 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, October 13/16, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 17, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    ALS, 8 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, October 19/20, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 2, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 4/5, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Clark Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 6, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 9/10, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 12, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 16, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Silver Springs, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 23, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 6 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 27, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 27, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 29/30, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 7, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 15, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 24, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 5 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, ca. January 4, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Murfeesboro, Tennessee - ALS, 12 pages (enclosed in letter dated January 10)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, January 10, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Murfeesboro, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 18, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 25, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, ca. January 26, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 29, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 8, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 10, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 13, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, February 19/22, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Murfreesboro, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, February 28, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Murfreesboro, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 3, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 19, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 20, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 21, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 25, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 2, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 3, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 8, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 9, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 14, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 17, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 3, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Clark Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 13, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, June 2/3, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    Columbus, Ohio - ALS, 8 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Murfreesboro, Tennessee - ALS, 3 pages
  - Mrs. G.D. Gibbons to Mrs. Milton Barnes, June 10, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, June 18, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, June 23, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, July 4, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Pelham, Tennessee - ALS, 6 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, ca. July 6, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    Pelham, Tennessee - ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, August 24, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Chattanooga, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, August 31, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    Chattanooga, Tennessee - ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 3, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    Chattanooga, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 10, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 27, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 2/3, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 14, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 26, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 30, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 1, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    Hickory, Pennsylvania - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 9, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 16, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Cambridge, Ohio - ALS, 8 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 21, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 22, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 27, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 30, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 8, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 18, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 20, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Knoxville, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 24, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Knoxville, Tennessee - ALS, 8 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 28, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 10, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Charlestown, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 13, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Charlestown, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 17, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 21, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Kingston, Georgia - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, June 6, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, June 27, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, July 6/7, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, August 17, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Cincinnati, Ohio - ALS, 3 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, August 19, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 15, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Cincinnati, Ohio - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 18, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 19, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, ca. September 21, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, September 22, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, September 28, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 6, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Cincinnati, Ohio - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 1, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Barnesville, Ohio - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, November 7/9, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Barnesville, Ohio - ALS, 8 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 10, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Franklin, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 14, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Pulaski, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, November 19, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 1, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 3, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 5, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 7, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 11, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 8 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, ca. December 13, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 19, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, ca. December 19, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 21, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 21/22, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, December 24, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 25, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, December 30, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 6, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 6, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, January 11, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Huntsville, Alabama - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 11, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, January 12, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Huntsville, Alabama - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 16, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 20, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January 26, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, January, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, January, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, January, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, February 2, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 4, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, February 12, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 20, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, February 23, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, February 25, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 3, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 7, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 10, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 10, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 13, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 16, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 18, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 19/20, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, March 24, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, March 25, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Dr. Charles Hood to Lt. Col. Milton Barnes, March 27, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 3, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    Bull's Gap, Tennessee - ALS, 2 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 3, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 5, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Blue Springs, Tennessee - ALS, 4 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 5, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 10, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    Blue Springs, Tennessee - ALS, 3 pages
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 11, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 11, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 17, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, April 20, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 26, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, April 28, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 1, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    Nashville, Tennessee - ALS, 3 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 1, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 4, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 8, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 10, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 12, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 22, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, May 27, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, May 30, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, June 1, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, June 2, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, June 5, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Telegram: Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, June 7, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    Telegram, handwritten, 1 page
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, June 11, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Milton Barnes to Rhoda Barnes, October 28, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Chatanooga, Tennessee - ALS, 1 page
  - Milton Barnes to Clarence C. Barnes, June 21, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    St. George's Island, Behring Sea - ALS, 9 pages
  - Rhoda Barnes to Milton Barnes, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Steubenville Female Seminary: Report on Miss Rhoda L. Allison, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    Steubenville, Ohio - report card for the quarter from November 1, 1852 - January 15, 1853
  - Annual Commencement of Muskingum College, September 25, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    New Concord, Ohio - graduation commencement program
  - Commission for the 97th Regiment Ohio Volunteer Infantry, September 16, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    Official commission form signed by Ohio Governor David Tod and Adjudant General of Ohio, Charles W. Hill
  - Photograph of Milton Barnes in uniform, ca. 1863-1865 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Engraving of Milton Barnes, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Rhoda Barnes, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tri-Monthly Report of the state of the Recruiting Service at Cambridge, Ohio, March 20, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Signed by Milton Barnes; report indicates 1 person enlisted (and 1 "disposable") between March 10th - 20th
  - Note to Hon. E.M. Stanton from E.D. Townsend, April 29, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Columbus, Ohio - short note indicating that armies arrived safely
  - Newspaper clipping for assembly meeting with Col. J.D. Taylor and Col. Milton Barnes, September 1876 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified note about partisan politics, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Anonymous, 1 page
  - Invitation of Milton Barnes to Reception of General Ulysses S. Grant, ca. December 1879 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Columbus, Ohio - Reception date is December 8, 1879
  - Ticket to Ulysses S. Grant Dinner, ca. December 1879 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Columbus, Ohio - Dinner date is December 12, 1879
  - Invitation of Milton and Rhoda Barnes to Grant Reception and Dress Hop., ca. December 1879 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Columbus, Ohio - Reception and Dress Hop date is December 12, 1879 at 8:30 PM
  - Envelopes formerly containing dried flowers, addressed to Mrs. M. [Rhoda] Barnes, ca. 1865 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Cambridge, Ohio
  - Note from Rhoda Barnes, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Recipient unidentified, 2 pages
  - Unidentified letters addressed to Col. Milton Barnes, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Typescript of Milton Barnes papers, correspondence Vol 3, 1864-1865 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Typescript not arranged chronologically
  - Typescript of Milton Barnes papers, correspondence Vol 1, 1863-1864, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Typescript of Milton Barnes papers, correspondence Vol 2, 1859-1865 (Box 4, Folder 2)